Contact

tusharkantgaur@yahoo.co.in

www.linkedin.com/in/tushar-kant-gaur-767358191 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Big Data Analytics Product Management User Experience (UX)

Certifications

Product Management: Building a Product Roadmap

Product Management: Building a Product Strategy

Tushar Kant Gaur

Senior Manager at American Express Gurgaon

Summary

Experienced Product Management Leader with a demonstrated history of working in the financial services industry. Skilled in Big Data Analytics, Product Requirements, Payments, Customer Experience, and Fraud Investigations. Strong consulting professional with a PGCBM focused in Business Mangement from XLRI Jamshedpur.

Experience

American Express 8 years 2 months

Senior Manager ,Product and Capabilities team July 2018 - Present (2 years 2 months) Gurgaon, India

Product Owner of client facing web reporting capability focused around T&E spend and compliance and helping the client to optimize their T&E policies with focus on compliance

Responsible for creation of new products /solutions and enhancements to existing client facing products with focus on program optimization and fraud & risk pertaining to questionable spend, policy abuse and bad payment behavior.

Synthesize requirements of clients especially pertaining to fraud & risk into a common set of platform and services capabilities with long-term vision in mind by working closely with regional sales and account development teams and the technology team

Create and perform go to market strategy by working with program management team, sales and account development teams, owners, legal, compliance, governance and operational risk teams

Leading the third-party relationships in terms of external data and capabilities

Responsible for adoption and measurement of online products by using relevant key performance indicators.

Manager, Product and Capabilities team March 2017 - July 2018 (1 year 5 months) Gurgaon, India

Enable American Express Global Commercial Services to rapidly build, iterate and enhance payment analytics reporting across all channels such as web and mobile with focus on spend optimization and fraud reduction

Lead a team that defined product requirements which involves writing of very clear, thorough and detailed user stories for complex features and product sets

Primary conduit between other business units, BU product managers, engineering and other applicable groups to ensure flawless integration of new and existing feature sets enabling high quality customer facing insights enabled reporting products

Manager, Commercial Insights team July 2015 - March 2017 (1 year 9 months) Gurgaon, India

Led a group of professionals responsible to design and deliver reporting and analytical solutions for the account development team and the clients, with a strong focus on actionable insights, quality and on-time delivery.

Identified opportunities to enhance process efficiency through increased standardization and automation, to reduce manual effort with focus on insights

Partnered with wider team to develop new capabilities (tools, data, processes) to enhance the service offerings, bringing efficiencies, improved visualization and better customer experience

Collaborated with the account development team for resigning of major corporate clients

Manager, Peformance Analytics team September 2014 - June 2015 (10 months) Gurgaon, India

Led the team which was responsible to design and deliver reporting and analytical solutions for the sales and account development of corporate cards team, with a strong focus on quality and on-time delivery.

Manager

July 2012 - September 2014 (2 years 3 months)

Gurgaon, India

Understanding campaign objective, requirement gathering and campaign analysis by collaborating with marketing teams across the globe

Responsible for managing the international project queue and creating operations reporting dashboard for leadership team using tableau

Developed operational reporting metrics and resource utilization dashboard by leveraging tableau for the leadership

Played a critical role in development of standard product set for all types of marketing measurement requests for international market and was part of the advisory board

Genpact

Business Analyst

April 2010 - July 2012 (2 years 4 months)

Gurgaon, India

Worked on projects pertaining to campaign targeting and evaluation for a leading pharmacy benefit manager (PBM) of US.

Responsible for streamlining the campaign targeting by developing standard codes using SAS

WNS Global Services

Analyst

May 2008 - April 2010 (2 years)

Gurgaon, India

Campaign targeting by Identifying the best customers for direct mailing of discount coupons basis various criteria followed by campaign evaluation

Education

XLRI Jamshedpur

PGCBM, Business Mangement · (2012 - 2013)

Uttar Pradesh Technical University

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Science · (2003 - 2007)